Why did you only choose students
within this school for your works of art?
なぜ 同じ学園内の生徒ばかりを素材に選んだのかな
This academy is a girls' boarding school.
全寮制女子学校というこの学園の教育方針を 槙島先生はどうお考えですか
What do you think of their education policy, Mr. Makishima?
We were so close.
あと一歩でしたね
Ouryou Rikako has already been put on the wanted list.
王陵璃華子はすでに指名手配されています
It's just a matter of time.
時間の問題です
She'll disappear.
消えるな
What?
Come with me. I'd like to talk with you.
ちょっと来い 話がある
What is it? If you have a problem with me, just spit it out.
何だよ
文句があるならはっきり言え
I'm sorry.
すまなかった
It was me who got emotional.
Looks like your culprit was real after all.
感情的になっていたのは俺の方だった
やつはお前の妄想じゃなかった
Don't worry about it.
気にするな
If you took everything Enforcers said seriously, you'd be a poor Inspector.
執行官の言うことを全て真に受けてたら 監視官は務まらない
That's how it is, right?
そういうもんだろ
But...
だが…
It feels like my quarry's tail just brushed the tip of my nose.
獲物の尻尾が鼻先をかすめたみたいな感じだ
I'm feeling better than I have in a long time, Gino.
俺は今 久しぶりにとてもいい気分だよ　ギノ
Dare ni mo miserarenai mono
My head is full of things
脑海里充斥着的喧嚣
誰にも見せられないもの
Atama no naka afurete
That I can never tell anybody of
谁都无法看见
頭の中溢れて
In this perfect world
Machigai sae mo nai sekai he
我在这个不会犯错的机械世界里
間違いさえも無い世界へ
In this perfect world
Machigai sae mo nai sekai he
I roam, a lost being
Mayoikonderu
一路行走一路彷徨
迷い込んでる
Arienai hodo surikomareteru
This world is impossibly hard on me
あり得ないほど擦り込まれてる
与你擦肩而过的次数多到近乎异常
Arienai hodo surikomareteru
This world is impossibly hard on me
It's an illusion that plays out before my eyes
Me ni mieru mono dake no "sekai" genshou
我眼里能看到的 就是我全部的世界
目に見えるものだけの“世界”現象
It's an illusion that plays out before my eyes
Me ni mieru mono dake no "sekai" genshou
Abakidaseru kana
Can I find its faults?
暴きだせるかな
能否打破它
Plastic tac tic
Plastic, all is plastic
Plastic Tac Tic
plastic tac tic
Plastic tac tic
Plastic, all is plastic
Mou dare mo okashiku narenai yo
Nobody is allowed to be insane
もう誰もおかしくなれないよ
所有人都习以为常
Kisama mo plastic beautiful world
You're made of plastic too, like this beautiful world
你也一样 plastic beautiful world
貴様もplastic beautiful world
In this beautiful world
Utsukushi sugiru sekai ni
美しすぎる世界に
在这个过于完美的世界里
Boku wa nazeka
There is something
僕はなぜか
我为什么
Hikari ga mienakute
That obscures all light for me
光が見えなくて
看不到光明的方向
Haretsu shite yuku kokoro ga
My heart tries to break out
心在一步步碎裂
破裂していく心が
And finds no answer
Mugen no rifurekushon
回音无限
無限のリフレクション
Secret kills for you
Secret remains for you
The secret remains for you
secret remains for you
为你留下这个秘密
Don't show me a dark future
Misekake no iro to
徒有其表的鲜艳色彩及未来
見せかけの色と
Mirai wo abakanai de
Nor a world of pretense
别打破它
未来を暴かないで
Keep it secret motion
Keep our motion secret
keep it secret motion
就让这个秘密继续秘密下去
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 TMR@10 校对:西西   后期:时末
#09: Paradise Fruit
Okay.
よし
Have you decided?
お決まりですか
Yep.
うん　この組み合わせでお気に入りに登録しておいて
Add this outfit to my favorites.
Roger!
了解です
Oh! Do you have a date?
もしかしてデートとか
I-It's not like that!
ちっ　違うよ
Holo team! Use the pattern that we discussed yesterday!
ホロ班　昨日の打ち合わせどおりのパターンで
Provided by the Cyberization Health Bureau,
Ministry of Welfare
Advanced Medical Treatments of the Future
That Will Change Your Life
Okay!
はい
Hmm... I'm not sure...
うーん　どうかな～
Isn't it a little too flashy? People might feel it's tacky instead.
ちょっと派手過ぎて 逆に安くねえかな
Well, we can try some other patterns as well.
じゃあ　違うパターンちょっと試してみますね
How about getting a present for your date?
デートのお相手にご贈答品はいかがですか
Also, I could arrange a bouquet to be delivered—
あとは花束のコーディネートも
Didn't I just say it's not like that?!
違うって言ってるでしょ キャンセル　メモリー削除
Cancel! Delete memory!
As you wish. Speculation circuit will be reset!
かしこまりました 推測回路　リセットしま～す
Candy, turn on some news.
キャンディ　何かニュース
The Ministry of Welfare uploaded a recommended video.
厚生省からお薦めの動画がアップされています
Then play that one.
じゃあそれで
Today, we have Mr. Senguji Toyohisa, a pioneer of whole-body cyberization
本日は全身サイボーグ化のパイオニア
and chairman of the Teito Network Construction Corporation,
地下再開発を進める帝都ネットワーク建設の会長
a company that works on underground redevelopment.
Chairman of the Teito Network
Construction Corporation
泉宮寺豊久さんにお越しいただきました
Senguji
Toyohisa
Thanks for having me.
よろしくお願いします
The use of cyborg technology for
medical purposes is now commonplace.
医療目的のサイボーグ技術は私たちの生活にすっかりなじんだものとなりました
However, it's still rare to see someone like Chairman Senguji who,
しかし 泉宮寺会長のように脳と神経系以外全てをサイボーグ化した例は
except for his brain and nervous system, is entirely cybernetic.
まだまだ珍しいものです
It's a mystery to me why other people
haven't given up those limiting bodies of theirs.
不思議なんですよ
なぜ みんな早く不自由な肉体を捨ててしまわないのか
Limiting, you say?
不自由…ですか
Plato said that our souls were imprisoned in our bodies.
肉体は魂の牢獄だとプラトンは言いました
You seem to be in a bad mood already, Kougami.
いきなり不機嫌そうですね 狡噛さん
When I tried to smoke, that thing tried to bite me.
たばこ吸おうとしたら そいつにかみつかれそうになったんだよ
What's your problem?!
んだ　こら
What was that about? Geez...
いきなり何なんですか　もう
Sorry.
悪いな
Hmm?
Well, please don't worry about it. I'm curious too, so I don't mind.
いえ　気にしないでください
私も　興味があるので
I'm finding new pleasures in my life all the time.
私の人生はますます楽しみを増している
I never expected that overcoming
aging would lead to such happiness.
老いを克服することがこれほどまでに幸福なこととは
It's the kind of thing you can't understand until you have a cybernetic body yourself.
機械の体を受け入れないかぎり 理解はできないでしょう
But even with the latest technology,
しかし 最新の技術をもってしても 脳の寿命は１５０年程度とされています
it's estimated that the brain's lifespan is about 150 years at most.
I hear that we're still quite a ways away from complete cyberization of the brain.
脳の完全な機械化はまだまだクリアできていない課題が山積みとか
If I take my brain to its limits, I can squeeze a bit more life out of it.
限界まで酷使すれば まだ私の脳には余裕がある
So I'm counting on them to find a breakthrough in the meantime.
その間にブレークスルーが起きることを期待しますよ
I see. If that actually happens, then...
なるほど もしもそれが起きたとしたら
That's right.
さよう　不死の時代の到来です
The era of immortality will have arrived.
It's said that God created man in his own image.
神は自分に似せて 人をつくったという
Isn't it about time for us humans to become a little more like God?
そろそろ　もう少し 人が神に似てもいいのでは
What do you think about gaining eternal
youth and immortality by becoming a cyborg?
狡噛さんはどう思います
サイボーグ化の不老不死って
I'm not interested.
興味ないな
Life as a latent criminal isn't the sort
of thing you'd want to go on forever.
潜在犯の人生は末永く続けたくなるようなもんじゃない
But... As society progresses, the rights of latent criminals may improve.
でも　いつかもっと社会制度が発達すれば
潜在犯の権利だって改善されるかも
No wonder your Psycho-Pass always manages to stay so clear.
あんたのサイコパス 濁りにくいわけだ
According to a survey,
アンケート調査によると 全身の５割を超えるサイボーグ化には
it seems that a majority of people have answered
that they feel reluctant to be more than 50% cyborg.
抵抗を感じると答えた方が大多数のようですが…
I do understand the reluctance that those people feel.
抵抗があるという人の気持ちは分かりますよ
In the end, it's a matter of degree.
結局は程度の問題なんですよ
For example, take yourself.
例えばあなた
You're quite the cyborg too.
あなたも立派なサイボーグですよ
But I don't use artificial arms, legs, or organs.
しかし　私は義手も義足も人工臓器も使っていません
You do, however, carry some form of
portable information terminal, am I right?
何らかの携帯情報端末を持っていますよね
Well, yes... but doesn't everyone?
それはまあ 誰でも持っているのでは
A costume device, too?
コス·デバイスも
Of course.
もちろん
And at home, you probably have
home automation and an AI secretary.
そして　家にはホームオートメーションとＡＩセクレタリー
Yes.
ええ
What would happen to you if all the data in those
devices was lost due to some kind of disaster or accident?
それらのデータが災害や事故によって一気に失われたら
あなたはどうなりますか
Well...
それは…
I wouldn't be able to do any work until it was restored.
復旧するまで何の仕事もできません
When you entrust so much of your
everyday life to those electronic devices,
自分の生活をそこまで電子的な装置に委託しているのに
the argument that you're not a cyborg isn't very convincing.
サイボーグではないと言っても説得力はありませんよ
To you, those portable terminals are already your second brain.
あなたにとって携帯端末はすでに第二の脳だ
Isn't that right?
違いますか
It can be said that the history of science is a history of the expansion of the human body's functionality.
科学の歴史は人間の身体機能の拡張
In other words, the history of man's cyberization.
つまり　人間機械化の歴史と言い換えても差し支えない
That's why it's a matter of degree.
だから　程度の問題なんです
No Trespassing
Private Property
Yes?
はい
Hey. It's me, Kougami.
どうも　狡噛です
Oh, hold on a sec.
ああ　ちょっと待って
I don't see much environment Holo in use here.
環境ホロをほとんど使ってませんね
He doesn't like that kind of stuff.
そういうのが嫌いな人なんだ
It's been a while, Professor Saiga.
お久しぶりです　雑賀教授
Stop calling me "professor". How many years do you think it's been since I quit?
教授はよしてくれよ
辞めて何年たつと思ってるんだ
Who's this young lady?
そっちのお嬢さんが…
I'm Tsunemori Akane, an Inspector at the
Public Safety Bureau. Thanks for seeing me today.
初めまして 公安局の監視官 常守朱です
今日は　よろしくお願いします
Come in, and welcome to my home.
入りたまえ　歓迎するよ
Clinical Psychology Special Lecture A
Sibyl Education Investigation Research Center
Is coffee okay?
飲み物はコーヒーでいいかな
Yes.
ええ
Ah, yes.
あっ　はい
Just as well, since coffee's all I've got.
といってもな コーヒー以外ないんだよ
Inspector Tsunemori Akane...
常守朱監視官
Yes?
はい
Are you from Chiba prefecture?
千葉県出身かな
Yes, I am.
そうですけど
Your athletic ability isn't bad, and yet...
君は運動神経は悪くないのに 何でだろう
I wonder why...
Yeah...
そう…泳げない
I wonder why you can't swim.
What?!
Both of your parents are still alive.
両親はまだどちらもご存命
They're worried about their only daughter not finding a boyfriend.
一人娘になかなか恋人ができないのを心配している
Umm...
They were opposed to you working at the Bureau, too.
公安局入りにも反対だった
And, your grandfather or grandmother...
そして　祖父か祖母…
It must be your grandmother.
うん　祖母だな
She treated you with great affection.
かわいがってもらった かなりのおばあちゃん子だね
It seems that you're quite the grandma's girl.
It's often true that the more time you
spend with the elderly during your childhood,
幼児期 高齢者と長く過ごした人間ほど
the better you can get along with
Holo Avatar AIs during your adult life.
成長してからホロアバターの人工知能と良好な関係を築くことが多い
You fit that pattern, Ms. Tsunemori.
そのパターンに常守さんも当てはまっている
Umm...
あの…
You're as sharp as ever, Saiga.
相変わらずですね　雑賀先生
How... did you do that?
今の…どうやったんですか
Simple observation.
ただ観察しただけさ
People manifest all sorts of signs unconsciously.
人は無意識のうちに様々なサインを発している
Once you get the knack of it, you can read those signs pretty easily.
コツさえ覚えれば 簡単にそのサインを読み取れる
Saiga Jouji...
雑賀譲二先生
You specialize in clinical psychology.
専門は臨床心理学
As I worked as a psychiatric examiner
and assisted in investigations and such,
精神鑑定や捜査協力なんかをしているうちに
my main focus shifted to criminal research before I knew it.
いつの間にか犯罪の研究に主軸が移ってしまったよ
I have two favors to ask you today.
今日は２つお願いがあります
Ask me anything.
何でも言ってくれ
First, I'd like you to give this Inspector an intensive short course.
一つはこちらの監視官に短期集中講義を
I'd like to learn about profiling and such.
プロファイリングとか時代遅れの方法ってことになってますけど
They say it's an outdated method, but I'm very interested in it.
すごく興味があって
Or rather, I became interested recently.
ていうか　最近興味が出てきて
I'm a hermit. I actually feel grateful for the opportunity to teach you.
こんな世捨て人に ありがたい話だよホントに
So, what's the other one?
で　もう一つは
I'd like to see the list of past course attendees that you keep with you.
先生が保管している今までの受講生名簿を見せてください
Is that a request from the Bureau?
それは公安局からの要請かな
No. It's a request from me.
いえ　個人的なお願いです
If it was an order, I would've turned it down.
もしも命令だったとしたら断ったところだ
Who are you looking for?
誰を捜している？
I think this guy must be the worst criminal to
have lived since the creation of the Sibyl System.
シビュラシステムの誕生以降 最悪の犯罪者だと思われます
What do you mean?
というと？
He's a high-level white-collar criminal
極めて高いレベルの知能犯
who most likely keeps himself in good health.
おそらく　肉体的にも頑健
Possessing a unique charisma,
he rarely kills people with his own hands.
特殊なカリスマ性を持ち
自分で直接手を下すことは少なく
Rather, he chooses to influence the minds of others.
他人の精神を支配し影響を与え
Much like a music conductor,
he orchestrates one crime after another.
まるで音楽を指揮するように犯罪を重ねていく男です
Kougami, please explain what "charisma" is.
狡噛
カリスマ性とは何だい？
I used it to mean the nature of a hero or a ruler.
英雄的　支配者的資質という意味で使いましたが…
I'd give that answer... twenty points.
２０点…かな
Charisma has three elements.
カリスマ性には３つの要素がある
The nature of a hero or a prophet,
英雄的 預言者的資質　あるいは
the ability to simply make you feel good when you're around them,
一緒にいて気持ちがいいというシンプルな空間演出能力
and the intelligence to eloquently talk about all sorts of things.
そして　あらゆることを雄弁に語るための知性
Of those, which elements does this guy you're looking for have?
狡噛が捜しているのはどのタイプかな
I think he has all of them.
全ての要素を備えていると考えられます
This is Shibata Yukimori, an art teacher at Ousou Academy.
桜霜学園美術教師　柴田幸盛
Well, that's who he's supposed to be,
ということになっているが
but it turns out that he's actually an old man in a
nursing home who has nothing to do with the academy.
実際は介護施設に収容されたまったく無関係な老人だった
His background profile was altered and used by our suspect when he pretended to be a teacher.
彼の経歴が改ざんされ
教員に成り済ます上で利用されていた
It's quite cruelly clever of him not to completely fake his background.
完全な偽造経歴じゃないところが
悪質かつ巧妙っすね
But he then chose to work as a teacher, placing himself right in the public eye?
しかし　教師なんて人目に触れる仕事に就くとは
Is he daring or just a fool?
大胆なのか間抜けなのか
Well, about that...
それがですね
All the video data was destroyed.
映像データは全てクラッシュ
The only thing we were able to salvage was a short sound file.
辛うじて残っていたのはほんの短い音声ファイルのみ
There are only two methods left: creating a
traditional photofit picture or drawing a composite sketch.
残された手段は昔ながらのモンタージュ写真と似顔絵作成の２つだけ
Of course, we tried both methods.
もちろん どちらもやってみました
From the sound of it, they didn't work?
その口ぶりからすると外れか
Right.
ええ
In the end, the only lead we have is
the blurry picture Sasayama took, right?
結局　佐々山が撮ったピンぼけの写真しか手掛かりはないってか
Did you end up getting anything out of that?
少しはあんたの役に立ったか？
Y-Yes, it helped a lot!
はい　とても
He's an incredible teacher.
すごい先生です
I don't understand why his lectures aren't in the Bureau's archives.
公安局のアーカイブに入ってないのが不思議でしかたありません
There's no way they'd put them in the archives.
アーカイブ化は無理だな
Did something happen?
何かあったんですか？
This was around the time that both the Sibyl
System and the university system existed together.
シビュラシステムと大学制度が同時に存在していたころの話だ
Saiga's special courses were set up for the Bureau's investigators.
公安局捜査官のために　雑賀先生の特別講義が設けられていた
But one day, a major concern came to light.
だがあるとき大問題が発覚した
The course attendees' Hues became
cloudier and their Crime Coefficients rose.
受講生の色相が濁り 犯罪係数が上昇したんだ
Well, not all of them.
まっ全員じゃないがね
A one-on-one lecture like the one you had today should be fine.
今日のようなマンツーマンの講義なら大丈夫だ
Besides, I don't see your Hue clouding that easily at all.
それにあんたは色相が濁りにくいたちだしな
But...
でも…
It's crazy that just listening to
lectures could raise your Crime Coefficient.
講義だけで犯罪係数が上がるなんて
Say you're at a dark swamp and you can't see the bottom.
底が見えない黒い沼がある
If you want to find out what's in that
swamp, you have no choice but to jump in.
沼を調べるためには飛び込むしかない
Saiga's used to it since he's dived in so many times already.
先生は何度も調査のために潜ったことがあって慣れている
But it's not like all his students can dive into that swamp and come back safely.
でも全ての生徒が沼に潜って無事に戻ってこれるわけじゃない
There are gaps in their abilities, not to mention their basic suitability.
能力差や単純に向き不向きもある
You seem like someone who'd dive right to the bottom... and yet come back safely.
狡噛さんは深くまで潜りそうですね
それでもちゃんと帰ってくる
Well, I don't know about that.
いや　どうだかな
At least, the Sibyl System decided that I couldn't come back.
少なくともシビュラシステムは
俺が帰ってこられなかったと判断した
What would you say is the most cunning animal?
最も狡猾で　いくら狩り殺しても絶滅の心配がない動物は何だと思う
One that's at no risk of extinction no
matter how many are hunted and killed?
That'd be humans.
人間でしょ
Too easy, huh?
簡単過ぎたな
These days...
今はもう…
they no longer issue hunting licenses under normal circumstances.
普通の狩猟は許可が下りない
I really appreciate what you've done for me, Makishima.
槙島君には感謝しているんだよ
That's not ivory... is it?
象牙…ではありませんね
I guess I haven't shown this one to you before.
まだ見せたことはなかったな
Excluding the mouthpiece, this pipe
is made from Ouryou Rikako's bones.
このパイプはマウスピース以外は王陵璃華子の骨だよ
I see.
When I'm touching it like this...
こうして触っていると…
my mind regains its youth.
心が若さを取り戻すんだよ
The souls of my terrified prey give me energy.
恐怖に震え上がる獲物たちの魂が私に活力を与えてくれる
You've overcome your body's aging.
肉体の老いは克服した
I guess that just leaves your mind?
あとは心 ですか？
Yeah, that's right.
そういうことだね
You maintain a healthy and sound life...
生命とは他の命を犠牲にすることで
by sacrificing other lives.
健やかに保たれる
But if people only seek youth for their bodies
だが　体の若さばかりを求め 心を養うすべを見失えば当然
and lose sight of the means to cultivate their minds,
it's only natural that it would lead to
an increase in the number of living dead.
生きながらに死んでいる亡者たちばかりが増えていく
Don't you think it's foolish?
愚かしいかぎりではないか
The energy that comes from the thrill of the hunt...
スリルによる活力
It's a dangerous reward that goes hand in hand with death, isn't it?
それは死と隣り合わせの危険な報酬ですな
That's right.
そうとも
In hunting, the tougher your prey is,
the fresher the youth you can gain from it.
狩りの獲物は手ごわいほどにみずみずしい若さが手に入る
With all that in mind,
そこまで仰せなら
I think I can arrange for your next prey to be most exquisite indeed.
次は飛び切りの獲物をご用意できるかと
Oh?
It's an Enforcer from the Public Safety Bureau.
公安局執行官
The Bureau?
公安局
His name is...
名前は…
In the end, I guess checking Professor
Saiga's lecture attendees list didn't help much.
結局　雑賀教授の受講者名簿は空振りでしたね
That's how it goes sometimes.
しかたがない
But if Makishima is a living person,
he's left a trace somewhere for sure.
だがマキシマが生きている人間なら
必ずどこかに足跡がある
I heard that you brought Inspector Tsunemori to Saiga Jouji.
常守監視官を雑賀譲二に引き合わせたそうだな
Yeah.
ああ
He did it because I asked him to.
それは　私が紹介を頼んで…
What are you playing at? Are you
trying to drag her into your problem,
どういうつもりだ　彼女を巻き添えにしたいのか
making her a latent criminal who strayed from the right path, like you?
貴様と同じ道を踏み外した潜在犯に
Wait a minute!
ちょっと待ってください　私を子供扱いしてるんですか
Why are you treating me like a child?
Because you are a child!
事実として君は子供だ
A brat who's confused about anything and everything!
右も左も分かってないがきだ
Why do you think we split the force into
Inspectors and Enforcers in the first place?
何のために監視官と執行官の区分けがあると思う
It's to avoid the risk of having healthy people's
Psycho-Passes get clouded by criminal investigations.
健常な人間が犯罪捜査でサイコパスを曇らせるリスクを回避するためだ
We use latent criminals, who can never return to society, in our place.
二度と社会に復帰できない潜在犯を身代わりに立てているからこそ
That's precisely how you're able to fulfill your duty while keeping a healthy mind!
君は自分の心を守りながら職務を遂行できるんだ
That's not teamwork!
そんなのチームワークじゃありません
Are we here to solve crimes or protect our own Psycho-Passes?
犯罪を解決するのと 自分のサイコパスを守るのと
Which one do you think matters more?!
いったいどっちが大切なんですか
Do you want to throw away your career?
君はキャリアを棒に振りたいのか？
Do you intend to sacrifice everything you've built so far?
ここまで積み上げてきたもの全てを犠牲にするつもりか？
It's...
私は…
It's certainly true that I'm new here.
私は確かに新人です
You're my senior, Inspector Ginoza, and I respect that.
宜野座監視官は尊敬すべき先輩です
But please don't forget that we're
on equal footing in terms of our rank!
しかし　階級上はまったくの同格ということを忘れないでください
I'm managing my Hue just fine.
自分の色相はちゃんと管理できています
You may be my senior, but I'd appreciate it
if you would refrain from questioning my ability
いくら先輩とはいえ　職場で執行官たちの目の前で
at the workplace and in front of the Enforcers!
私の能力に疑問符をつけるような発言は慎んでいただきたい
I can't believe he...
あんな言い方…
Where are you going?
どこに行くんだい
I'm going to file a complaint with the bureau chief.
局長を通して抗議します
Any chance of you passing on that, missy?
やめておいてくれないかな お嬢ちゃん
But...
でも
Inspector Ginoza's father is a latent criminal.
宜野座監視官はな 父親が潜在犯なんだ
What?
えっ
He was a child when the Sibyl
System had just been put into operation.
あいつの子供時代ってのは まだシビュラ判定が実用化されて間もないころでな
Terrible misunderstandings and rumors
about latent criminals were common in those days.
世間では潜在犯に対する過剰な誤解やデマが横行していた
If a family member happened to show a high Crime Coefficient,
親兄弟から犯罪係数が計測されたというだけでその家族までもが
that alone caused the rest of the family to be treated as if they were the same.
同類の扱いを受けた
I'm sure he suffered quite a bit.
さぞやつらい思いをしたことだろうさ
When a detective gets deeply involved in an investigation,
刑事が捜査に深くのめり込めば結局は
in the end the Sibyl System starts keeping an
eye on them just like it does with the criminals.
シビュラシステムから犯罪者の同類としてマークされるようになる
Remember what I said about committing crimes and cracking down on them?
犯す側も取り締まる側も
They're two sides of the same coin. The phenomenon called "crime".
同じ犯罪という現象に直面していることに違いはない
We have Enforcers now, but before they created that position,
今みたいに執行官なんて役職ができる前には
there were many detectives who
ended up as latent criminals that way.
そうやって潜在犯と診断された刑事が大勢いた
Inspector Ginoza's father was one of them.
宜野座監視官の父親もその一人だ
I didn't know...
そうだったんですか…
That's why he won't allow the other Inspectors to take risks on their own.
だからあいつは 自ら進んで危険を冒すやつを許せない
Even then, Kougami, his former colleague, suffered the same fate.
なのに　同僚だった狡噛も…
Yes, I know.
ええ　知ってます
He feels as though he was betrayed twice.
父親と　相棒に
First by his father and then by his colleague.
二度も　裏切られたという思いがあるんだ
That's why he acts like that toward you.
だから　お嬢ちゃんに対する態度もあんなふうになっちまう
But even so...
でも　だからって…
You're right.
間違っちゃいないさ
Don't you have family and friends of your own, missy?
お嬢ちゃん　あんたにだって家族や友達がいるんだろ？
If your Psycho-Pass gets clouded,
あんたのサイコパスが曇ったら
those people will suffer the same hardships Nobuchika did.
今度はその人たちが伸元と同じ苦しみを背負うことになる
We Enforcers are here to prevent that.
そうならないために俺たち執行官がいる
Do you think Kougami feels that way too?
狡噛さんもそんなふうに思ってるんでしょうか？
He used to.
以前はな
But now...
だが　今は…
I think he's oblivious to anything
that's not related to that Makishima guy.
例のマキシマってやつのこと以外
目に入らなくなっちまってるのかもしれん
I've no interest in capturing him alive.
私は生け捕りにしないよ
Is that okay with you?
いいのか？
Of course.
もちろん
What would even be the point?
どうして生け捕りなんて？
It seems that you haven't noticed it yourself, so I'll tell you this:
君は気付いていないようだから言っておくが
Kougami Shinya...
狡噛慎也
That name always seems to bring a smile to your face.
その名前を　口にするとき
君はとても楽しそうなんだよ
Fearii teeru wa
It seems all fairy tales
御伽話（フェアリーテイル）は
童话般的美好
It seems all fairy tales
Fearii teeru wa
Sakki shinda mitai
Are dead
さっき死んだみたい
在刚刚已经死去
Are dead
Sakki shinda mitai
Renga no byoutou de
In a hospital ward of brick stones
煉瓦の病棟で
瓦墙下的病房
In a hospital ward of brick stones
Renga no byoutou de
Umaku utaenakute
My voice is too coarse to sing
うまく歌えなくて
在这里我无法歌唱
My voice is too coarse to sing
Umaku utaenakute
Kiri ni kemuru yoru
Outside in the foggy haze
灰灰蒙蒙的夜
霧に煙る夜
Outside in the foggy haze
Kiri ni kemuru yoru
Ukabe akai tsuki
A red moon glows
悬浮飘红的月
浮かべ赤い月
A red moon glows
Ukabe akai tsuki
Hora mite watashi wo
Look at me
ほらみて　私を
快 看我
Look at me
Hora mite watashi wo
Me wo sorasanai de
Do not avert your gaze
别移开你的视线
目を逸らさないで
Do not avert your gaze
Me wo sorasanai de
Kuroi tetsu goushi no naka de
Behind black bars
黑黑的铁栅背后
黒い鉄格子の中で
Watashi wa umarete kitanda
I was born
Behind black bars
Kuroi tetsu goushi no naka de
I was born
Watashi wa umarete kitanda
我来到这个世界
私は生まれてきたんだ
Akui no daishou wo negae
I wish there were a punishment for evil
I was born
Watashi wa umarete kitanda
I wish there were a punishment for evil
Akui no daishou wo negae
悪意の代償を願え
祈祷恶的代价
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
Always I need you
I wish there were a punishment for evil
Akui no daishou wo negae
Always I need you
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
如你所愿给你吧
望むがままにお前に
Always I need you
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
Saa ataeyou seigi wo
Now, grant us justice
Always I need you
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
Now, grant us justice
Saa ataeyou seigi wo
さあ与えよう正義を
给与你
Kowashite kowasareru mae ni
Before chaos takes us all
Now, grant us justice
Saa ataeyou seigi wo
Before chaos takes us all
Kowashite kowasareru mae ni
壊して　壊される前に
破坏掉正义 在自身毁灭之前
Inga no daishou wo harai tomo ni yukou
Pay the price of fate and let us go together,
Before chaos takes us all
Kowashite kowasareru mae ni
Pay the price of fate and let us go together,
Inga no daishou wo harai tomo ni yukou
付出因果的代价
因果の代償を払い
一起走吧
共に行こう
Namae no nai kaibutsu
Nameless beasts
Pay the price of fate and let us go together,
Inga no daishou wo harai tomo ni yukou
Nameless beasts
Namae no nai kaibutsu
名前のない怪物
无名怪兽
Nameless beasts
Namae no nai kaibutsu
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".